numbersusa.com 2012-06-24

# Privacy Policy | NumbersUSA - For Lower Immigration Levels

####  Commitment to Your Privacy 

Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us, and we respect your desire to have a satisfying and safe online experience. The interactive portions of this website are owned and operated by NumbersUSA Action, a non-profit, non-partisan, public policy organization. Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

Because we collect certain information from you in order to send faxes on your behalf and provide you with focused opportunities for action, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

#### Information NumbersUSA Action Gathers and Tracks

We gather two types of information about users:

  * Information that you and other users provide through optional, voluntary submissions, such as contact information to appear on faxes you choose to send, registration information to receive our action emails, or the results from your participation in polls and surveys. This would also include both solicited and unsolicited comments posted on our website or sent to us via email.
  * Information that we gather through aggregate or indirect tracking. This information is collected in order to provide you a more focused experience and to help us better tailor our content and alerts to readers' needs. It also helps us better understand the demographics of our audience in order to be more effective.

#### Use of Information

NumbersUSA Action uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience on our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out action emails and alerts and to enable users to send faxes and participate in polls, surveys, and forums. We send out action emails and newsletter alerts to subscribers on an irregular schedule based on their level of interest and the level of activism required to make a difference on an issue. NumbersUSA Action never shares mailing lists with any third parties, including sponsors or partners.

We also use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in the Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters.

However, we do keep track of which faxes you have sent for the express purposes of making sure you don’t get prompted to send a fax twice and, to a lesser extent, to determine future faxes you may be interested in.

At times, NumbersUSA Action creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for sponsors and partners. This allows us to fund raise more effectively. Rest assured that these aggregate reports will never contain personally identifying information.

#### Sharing of the Information

NumbersUSA Action uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our sponsors and supporters understand our demographics. This is essential to keeping our service non-profit. Rest assured that we will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

#### Security

NumbersUSA Action operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers.

#### Cookies

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. This is standard practice for many interactive websites, and your browser contains many security measures to limit the use of a cookie. The cookie itself does not contain personal information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. For example, it contains your username and a seemingly random string of letters and numbers. A cookie is not a virus or adware, and it cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. NumbersUSA Action uses cookies to track user traffic patterns and recognize returning users so they don’t have to log into the site every time they return.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in comments, forums and surveys and to send faxes.

#### Opt-Out Policy

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:

  * Opting not to register to receive our action alerts and other emails. We also provide multiple levels of activism with respective levels of email alerts.
  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas; we will not gather any personally identifiable information from users who select this option.

#### Your Consent

By using the interactive portions of this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by NumbersUSA Action. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. In the case that we do make significant changes to the information disclosure portion of this privacy policy, we will make a good faith effort to give you notice of such changes via email, including an option to opt out. However, we do not anticipate such changes.

If at any time you decide to withdraw your consent, you may do so in writing to the following address. We will remove from our servers any personally identifying information, such as name, email addresses, etc.

1601 N. Kent Street  
Suite 1100  
Arlington, VA 22209
